And this lesson, we're going to see how to work with multiple extend or interrupt.
So I'm going to create a new project from.
All right.
Yeah.
Click over here.
You project.
Also liked my board.
This team to four.
One, one.
Or just like the nuclear board here.
And I'm going to disable Claire, or the pin out was a clip in out over here
and I'm going to start off.
I know we have just a single button on the nuclear board, but we would find a way to run this experiment.
I'm going to set a wire.
P.S. 13 over here, which is where our push button is connected to extend or interrupt GPL, you extend
or interrupt 13.
And then I'm going to set P five to our ality, which is simply GPL, your output like this.
We can use Spears zero as our next button, although there is no second button on the board.
We can nominate peers you over here.
So I'm going to go to pin p0 and said as as GPL, you extend or interrupt you like this.
Okay.
So we can make our experiment a bit more interesting by 10 in the early days on using P.S. 13, which
is where our push button is connected and turn it off using PSU so we can go to our systems view and
then click on our GPL.
You over here to setup the pins.
I'll click over here to open it.
So I'll start off by clicking on, um.
We have our peers who are here.
We know it selected its default mode as extend or interrupt mode with Brize in edge trigger.
That is fine.
A whopping five is said to, um, output, Push-Pull.
That is fine as well.
These are peers.
Right.
So the spears, you extend or interrupt, rise and, uh, rise, rising age trigger.
P.S. 13, we want to change that to fall in age external interrupt mode with falling edge trigger detection.
Right.
OK.
Once this is done, we've got to go to the NVC tub.
And and they will all interrupt enabled us and then enable this.
Now we can go ahead and generate our project, come to generate code over here.
I'll call this or call this multiple.
External.
Interrupts and then also likes my tune change over here is the esteemed 32 Cube.
And then we can click over here to generate.
This is our project.
I'll clean up a bit.
So this all may not seem far.
And if we come down here, would see all of the code calibrated in the GPL.
You in it.
We have to interrupt.
And to see further interrupt information, we can come to the SDM 32 F4 on the score.
I did not see this fall over here and now we'll see our two interlocked, uh oh, two interrupt handlers.
So we have 10 or 15 to 10.
I RCU handler.
And this is what would handle the interrupt request for P.S. 13.
And then we have extend or interrupt zero hour cue handler.
And this, of course, is DPL you pin zero.
OK, so now we have to implement a while Kobuk for interrupt.
So we have to go to our GPL you module.
So I come to drive us over here.
How drivers sors and then G.P.A. you don't see.
And we can simply start off by searching the week keyword our search on that score on a score week.
And we have this callback function here.
Oh, GPL, you, XDR.
Kobuk.
So we can just copy this, reimplement this.
No, I mean, let's see file.
So I copy this and then I'll come up here.
I can close this.
I'll come up here and put this here like this.
And then I would delete the weak key word.
Yeah.
OK.
So you may be wondering, we've got one callback function, but we've got to interrupt.
How do we work with this?
And there is a single parameter over here which is GPL you pin.
OK.
We can do this by using an if statement.
We can simply check what a pain is to interrupt coming from and then we execute.
Well, we want to execute.
So over here I can simply see if this parameter here, GPL yappin.
If this equals G play, you pin zero, which is the same as our peers zero.
If this, of course GPA point zero, then we want to do something here.
And we said I would do something will be to turn on the ality, but do something.
And over here, we can see if the GPA you pin a course GPA, you pin 13.
Want to do something again?
OK, so over here, you can do whatever you want, but I'm just going to turn on the here.
Turn off the ality here and turn it on in the next interrupt.
So I'll see how GPI you.
And then two, turn on.
We use the right pin.
Right.
Been like this.
And then this takes the port, which is GPL.
You see, that's where the is connected.
The PIN number is keeping you on the scorpion on this score five.
And then we want to write zero to it.
Want to turn it off.
So we use reset.
So we say G.P.A. you on the Scorpion and the score reset like this.
And over here, if the interrupt is coming from P.S. 13, we want to turn on the depen.
So we say G.P.A., you hold GPI, you on the score, right.
PIN like this and then we pass the same thing.
GPL U.
A.
And then the the penis G.P.A..
You pin five.
Cause that is where the it is connected p a five.
You pin on the score five.
And we want to do cheapie.
You.
No scorpion on this corset sets means.
Right.
One to it, okay.
We have this over here.
So from this arrangement, I hope you can tell that we cannot have, uh, two PIN numbers in a multiple
interrupt arrangement.
And what I mean by two PIN numbers is that if you have the same PIN number but different port, you
can all use multiple interrupt.
You have to have different pin numbers, if any can be the same ports, but different PIN numbers.
The reason why that is, is that what is taken here is the PIN number.
So pin zero here means it could be pin zero four.
Put a pin zero for ports B, C, D, E, F, et cetera.
So you cannot have pin zero for port A as one extent or interrupt and pin zero for port to be as an
ETA as another extend or interrupt cause there would be no way to differentiate the two of them.
Right.
So we can go ahead and build a project or click over here.
I have one error here because of the.
This would pin here should be all cup two letters.
So appealed again.
It appealed successfully.
I'll get onto the board by clicking on this.
Selectors say, okay.
I say, OK.
Here we are here.
We can click here to run.
Right.
So you can try this on your board so you can simply connect on the external button to the P zero.
This is the, uh, that nuclear user guide we downloaded.
This is the position of P is you.
It over here.
You can just use this P note.
Oh.
This one here.
This is how I bought a four one one r e p.
Is you.
Is this pin over here.
Right.
So based on the setup, if you have more interrupt, you can just use the if statement to deal with
them one by one like that.
So that's all there is.
And I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.